SAAD KHAN JADOON

Senior Land Surveyor (SAUDI ARABIA)

EMAIL: Saadisaadkhan677@gmail.com

CONTACT: +966 53 505 1875

IQAMA NUM: 2555640115 Immediatly Joining

SUMMARY:

With over 8+ years of experience typically in Land surveying (BUILDING, ROAD,INFRASTRUCTURE AND FACADE WORK). I have excellent set of skills to fulfill the job in the required manner. Below is the list of my major key skills as Land Surveyor: Precision layout survey Measuring angles and distances for Network Adjustment & calculation with Micro Survey Star Net* least square network adjustments software. Excellent knowledge in latest surveying instruments Robotic Total Stations, GPS, and Auto levels. Very well familiar with Computer Aided surveying applications especially AutoCAD, Micro Survey, Star Net, Excel Meas, Surfer 11, MS Office Package etc. As well as a quick learner who rapidly becomes familiar with new techniques & environment. Willing to relocate: Anywhere

PERSONAL DETAILS

Eligible to work in country: Yes

Industry: Civil Engineering, Construction, Technology

POSITION: Senior Land Surveyor

(Infra Structure Work)

COMPANY: Mahmood Saeed Steel Industries - MSSI LOCATION: Red Sea Global International Airport - Umluj

DURATION: JUNE 2024 To Present **Project:RSG Airport- Steel Structure**

Responsibilities:

As a Land Surveyor currently working in there my responsibilities are to:

Led and managed land surveying operations, ensuring precise measurements for site layout, boundaries, and construction activities.

Conducted topographic surveys, geodetic control, and stakeout surveys for foundations, utilities, and infrastructure.

Utilized advanced surveying equipment and software (e.g., Total Stations, GPS, AutoCAD) to provide accurate data for design and construction teams. Supervised junior surveyors, providing technical guidance and ensuring the accuracy of survey data.



POSITION: Land Surveyor

(Infra Structure Work)

COMPANY: ALMAJAL ALARABI GROUP

LOCATION: NEOM, KSA

DURATION: JUNE 2023 To MAY 2024 **Project:** NEOM PROJECT NRC5

Responsibilities:

As a Land Surveyor currently working in there my responsibilities are to:

There my responsibilities Are to:

Supervision of installation and construction of Raft Foundation, Retaining Walls and maintain slope

Marking & Alignment of Anchor Cage Of Anchor Bolts.

Arrangement of Earth Moving Equipment and Civil excavation activities like excavation,

Slope Cutting for stone pitching, leveling and compaction

Check control & implement the designed horizontal & vertical profile of Structure.

Preparing the As Built Reports for Design modifications.

Check control & implement the designed horizontal & vertical profile of structure

WORK EXPERIENCE

POSITION: Land Surveyor (Infra Structure Work)

COMPANY: Yousef Maror CO LOCATION: UMLUJ,KSA

DURATION: Feb 2023 To JUNE 2023 **Project:** RED SEA PROJECT UMLUJ

Responsibilities:

As a Land Surveyor currently working in there my responsibilities are to:

There my responsibilities Are to:

Supervision of installation and construction of Raft Foundation, Retaining Walls and maintain slope Marking & Alignment of Anchor Cage Of Anchor Bolts.

Arrangement of Earth Moving Equipment and Civil excavation activities like excavation, Slope Cutting for stone pitching, leveling and compaction

Check control & implement the designed horizontal & vertical profile of Structure.

Preparing the As Built Reports for Design modifications.

Check control & implement the designed horizontal & vertical profile of structure

POSITION: Land Surveyor

(Building Work)

COMPANY: Sinopic Construction Company (KSA)

LOCATION: Safaniya, KSA

DURATION: June 2022 To Feb 2023 **Project:** Tanajib Gas Plant Aramco project

Responsibilities:

As a Land Surveyor currently working in there my responsibilities are to:

Check control & implement the designed horizontal & vertical profile of steel structure.

Allignments of steel structure vertically & horizontally.

Kepping the precast foundation its original location by layout.

Layout of brackets & embed for façade contractor for curtain wall installation.

Traversing of control points & bench marks & adding additional points if necessary for day to day setting out activities.

Setting out of grid lines for façade activities.

Setting out of grid lines & F.F.L levels for interior fit out jobs.

Preparing data out of Auto Cad Drawings for site layout activities.

built reports of structures in Auto cad.

POSITION: Land Surveyor

(INFRA Work)

COMPANY: TIEJUN Trading & Contracting Company (KSA)

LOCATION: UM LAJ, KSA

DURATION: March 2020 To May 2022 Project:

Red Sea Development (Road & Pipe Line Project). Responsibilities

Layout for Pipe Line Location As Per Design Drawing..

Alignment and levels check based on approved drawings.

After completing site survey works inspecting and validating found accept tolerance or not.

Topographical survey for existing structure. Traversing of Benchmarks & control points.

Coordination with Site Engineer regarding site situation.

Making new Benchmarks and establishing accurate values.

Processing and analyzing the site survey data.

Validate for new Benchmarks from contractor and establishing accurate values at site.

Endorse with submitting on NGL/OGL survey data to analyzed and finalized with comments

Contour and profile drawing have to be checked Responsible for all the survey works and construction activities of modification of new alignment of bridges and culverts etc.

Check Stakeout points for sanitary, storm water, potable water, Irrigation works and

substation with electrical power Cable routes

Support & Co-ordinate with survey work to prepare necessary drawings from site conditions.

Control to maintain drawing levels in internal concrete structures and road layers.

Systematically to followed benchmarks in site conditions.

Utilities works Slope level retains to complete the line for limit of tolerance.

Micro tunnel shaft alignments and inside the shaft level have to check regular interval basis.

Ensure to safety procedure establish in shafts before go to inspections.

POSITION: Land Surveyor

(Building Work)

COMPANY: Al Osais Contracting Company, Jubail

LOCATION: Jubail

DURATION: March 2019 to 2020

Projects:

Royal Commission Jubail Housing Project RC 15 Responsibilities:

structures and providing levels for different kinds of building structure.

Monitoring and executing site works based on approved design drawings for alignment and levels.

Layout for column points of building.

Alignment and levels check based on approved drawings.

After completing site survey works inspecting and validating found accept tolerance or not.

Topographical survey for existing structure.

Traversing of Benchmarks & control points.

Providing levels of cut & fill for the excavation area.

As-built survey for the existing condition of the natural surface for quantity calculations.

Preparing reports of slab edges in Cad format.

Coordination with Site Engineer regarding site situation.

Making new Benchmarks and establishing accurate values.

Working as a Land Surveyor my responsibilities were to provide layout for minor & major

POSITION: Land Surveyor

(Building & Road Work)

COMPANY: Discon Contracting Company, Islamabad Pakistan

LOCATION: Islamabad

DURATION: May 2013 to Jan 2016

Working as a Land Surveyor my responsibilities were to provide layout for minor & major

Projects:

Bahria Town Islamabad. Responsibilities:

structures and providing levels for different kinds of building structure.

Monitoring and executing site works based on approved design drawings for alignment and levels.

Layout for column points of building.

Alignment and levels check based on approved drawings.

After completing site survey works inspecting and validating found accept tolerance or not.

Topographical survey for existing structure.

Traversing of Benchmarks & control points.

Providing levels of cut & fill for the excavation area.

As-built survey for the existing condition of the natural surface for quantity calculations.

Preparing reports of slab edges in Cad format.

Coordination with Site Engineer regarding site situation.

Making new Benchmarks and establishing accurate values.

Support & Co-ordinate with survey work to prepare necessary drawings from site conditions.

Control to maintain drawing levels in internal concrete structures and road layers.

Processing and analyzing the site survey data.

EDUCATION

Diploma of Associate Engineer in Civil Technology

INSITUTE: Pakistan Army Topographical School

DURATION: March 2011 to May 2013

A-Level or equivalent in Matriculation

INSITUTE: Pine Hills Public school DURATION: May 2003 to March 2005

AutoCAD

INSITUTE: Autodesk – Rawalpindi DURATION: October 2014 to March 2015

SKILLS

- Land Survey (7 years)
- Ms Office package (4 years)
- AutoCAD (2 years)
- Civil 3D (2years)
- Leica Geo System (1 years)

LANGUAGE

ENGLISH: ExpertARABIC: GoodURDU: Fluent